# NABIN PAUDYAL

#### **Software Engineer and Python Instructor**

⊠ npaudyal321@gmail.com ⊕www.navinpoudel.com.np mwww.linkedin.com/in/navinpoudel ⊕www.github.com/naween321

### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

An engineering graduate (UG) from Tribhuvan University, Nepal looking forward to pursuing a master's degree in computer science, with a focus on AI and machine learning. Proficient in software development with over three years of industry experience, I aspire to be an industry expert and a trainer in the field of software development AI and machine learning.

## **EXPERIENCES**

### Python and Django Instructor

#### **Broadway Infosys**

Feb 2023 – Running Kathmandu, Nepal

- Instructing Python and Django to the students of undergraduate level.
- Leading software engineering bootcamps in different public and private colleges in Nepal.
- Instructing government officials in different governmental departments of Nepal.
- Company website: https://broadwayinfosys.com/

# Software Engineer

## **Insight Workshop**

Jul 2019 – Nov 2022 Kathmandu, Nepal

- Built an online application (Level Up) as a principal engineer for software engineering training. Primarily created web APIs for the product using Python and Django Rest Framework.
- Launched the Level Up project in 2020 and saw an average increase in active users from 100 to around 1000.
- Lead multiple client projects of the company. Directly communicated with project clients for the requirements gathering and delivered the software within the provided deadlines.
- Mentored new hires and trainees at the company.
- Company website: https://insightworkshop.io/

## Software Engineering Instructor

#### **Insight Workshop Academy**

Jun 2020 – Nov 2022 Kathmandu, Nepal

- Taught Python and Django online to over 300 students during the initial COVID shutdown in 2020.
- Created video content on programming languages and frameworks like Python, Django, REST Framework, React, and related learning materials.

- Taught 12-15 students in a physical classroom and 50-60 students online using the LevelUp platform, with new sessions beginning each month on a rolling basis.
- Academy website: https://insightworkshop.io/academy

#### Academic Lecturer

#### Arniko College of Business and Tech, Tribhuvan University

Apr 2022 – Sep 2022 Kathmandu, Nepal

- Taught the first-year BCA students (Bachelor in Computer Application) the academic mathematics course, which included chapters on Linear Algebra, Coordinate Geometry and Vectors.
- College website: https://aranikocollege.com/

#### **Project Coordinator**

#### Robotics Club, Kathmandu Engineering College

Apr 2017 – Mar 2018 Kathmandu, Nepal

- Conducted workshops and competitions and mentored college juniors with their academic projects.
- Worked as a lead instructor in a 'Microcontroller' workshop at United Technical College, Chitwan.

### **EDUCATION**

## Bachelor in Electronics & Communication Engineering

# Kathmandu Engineering College, Tribhuvan University, Kathmandu

Nov 2014 - Jan 2019

Major: Big Data, Computer Networks, Image Processing

# **Higher Secondary Education**

#### United Academy, Kathmandu

Jun 2012 – Apr 2014 Major: Physics, Mathematics and Chemistry

## TRAINING AND CERTIFICATION

- Completed 12-weeks Software Engineering bootcamp organized by Insight Workshop Academy. (July 2019)
- Supervised Machine Learning course from Coursera.
   https://coursera.org/verify/ZMNQZEN75Q7N (April 2023)
- Advanced Python

https://www.linkedin.com/learning/certificates/5e22aa1ab2225cdd5f26ea5fc02f74d15f3fc99 839f3daced39a7e4556084477 (Feb 2024) REST APIs Architecture
 https://www.linkedin.com/learning/certificates/f87b40e925d864a0dbed8a27fef3ad08ec7e73
 0c44f529dba102af648623b969 (Feb 2024)

#### **KEY SKILLS**

- Excel, Python, Jupyter Notebook, MS Office 365, Google Suite
- Curriculum development, teaching, coordination and communication
- Languages: English, Nepali

#### **TECHINCAL SKILLS**

- Languages/OS: Python, JavaScript, C++, Linux, SQL
- Cloud: EC2, S3, Lambda, Cloudflare, Nginx, Docker, Firebase
- Libraries/Frameworks: NumPy, SciPy, pandas, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, Django, Django Rest, Flask, React

### **PROJECTS**

### **Level Up – An Online Software Engineering Training App**

- Used React for the front-end, Django Rest Framework to develop APIs, Postgres for the database and AWS and Cloudflare for the cloud-related services. Incorporated FFMPEG (Fast Forward Moving Picture Experts Group) for chunking the video content uploaded to the platform.
- Implemented quiz, chat & video calling features in the project.
- Project link: https://levelup.com.np/

# **Dhukka – Service Provider Application**

- An application that links customers with the service providers like plumbers, electricians and bike riders (ride-sharing).
- Integrated nearest service provider search, shortest path algorithm and service fare calculations. Created REST APIs using Django Rest Framework and google map APIs for locations.

## **IoT Based Home Automation System**

• College final year project to make a smart home system with devices connected over the internet and featured with anti-theft, face recognition and fire-alarm systems. Implemented CNN (Convolution Neural Network) for face recognition.

### **Sunlight Tracking Solar Panel**

• College junior project in which a solar panel efficiently followed the solar light. Got a practical understanding of transistors, microcontrollers, sensors and other electronic components. The primary board of the project was Arduino-programmed

### **Line Following Robot**

• Built a competition-winning project in my college junior year that was able to follow a black line on a white surface. The primary board of the project was AVR-programmed.

# **MISCELLANEOUS**

- Nepal Engineering Council, grade 'A' engineer
- Former secretary and club service director of a Rotaract Club in Nepal
- Worked on the women empowerment campaign and provided training on social media security to middle-aged people.
- Provided Python training to the officials of the Forest Department of the Government of Nepal.
- **Hobbies:** Music, Soccer, Cricket, Travelling, Content Creating, Reading Books **My YouTube:** https://www.youtube.com/@codesoar8474